Hello friends, Namaskar,
definitely subscribe to the channel, please
Talk Market Classes, if you want, you can follow this channel too, you
can subscribe,
add the bell icon here also and definitely select all and keep it, it will be found
in the description, so friends,
for now let's start this video,
just like on our normal screen and on a
daily basis, you know that different
news updates keep coming here
and one such update is coming out here right now,
definitely means even if you are
not in the share market,
this news can be very important for you people,
so exactly
what is the news, where is it coming from and definitely
you are trying to get more detailed information about it
because we are currently seeing this thing happening,
so friends, you all
know that the Government of India keeps making different laws
here and if we
talk like this, then you people must be aware of a very big department,
IRDAI IAS
department, that is, it is a regulatory body,
if we talk about the head department of insurance, then  It can be seen,
like the regulatory body of the share market
is also there, the head of the bank
is RBI, similarly we get
to see the head of insurance in IRDAI, so
whatever decision it takes, it gets implemented all over India,
meaning if this is coming to your mind
that in which state this role will be
applicable, then this rule can be
seen being applicable all over India,
so what is it related to, then this is the
head body of insurance, it is the regulatory body,
so see the news related to insurance,
right now there are many types in insurance too, so
if we talk about car
insurance, which we get to see in general insurance
or if you want, we
can also say non-life insurance category, in that
we get to see this data,
so car insurance means if you have a
car, then definitely
this video is very
important for you people, so if we
talk about RBI, friends, it is being seen to be very strict right now
and if
we talk about
IIB, that is  Insurance Information Bureau
of India has all the data
related to insurance, friends, you
can see that this is the head department, it is
such a bureau that all the data related to insurance is
collectively
available with them and right now if we
talk about which insurance, let's
talk about tax insurance, so IRDAI
friends, is taking a decision here that
while buying a car, you know that you have to
take insurance and many times
we have also seen that after that the
insurance also has to be renewed, so
many people avoid it, so
now IRDAI is getting strict,
100% what you will have to do now, you will have to
travel with insurance,
if you travel without insurance, then
definitely you are going to face
problems in the future and
you all know the information related to this,
as I told you, it is kept here with IIB,
from there this information is going to be collected,
as the information will be connected, then where will it be
sent, Department of
Transportation,  The information will go there,
right now if we look at the Department of Transportation,
we get
to see it at different places state wide and if
we see any information going there, then we will come
to know
how many people have vehicles and the
insurance is active on it and how many people's
insurance means renewal is pending here, all these
things will be known and those who
have vehicles and they have
not taken insurance or if you can say it has
not been renewed and it has expired, then they will get a
notice, yes friends, a notice is
going to go here, not only a notice but a
fine will also be imposed, how much will the
fine be, right now it is being told that a
fine of around ₹ 2000 can also be imposed on you here,
so due to this thing, you
people should be alert, if you have a vehicle then
check once, all this
information is being said, just in the coming days, the news has just
come, so a date will be given, maybe
after that we will get to see all these things getting implemented
because if it is seen,
those who will have to
renew their insurance again  If it has expired then should we
give time or not, then
definitely some time can be given and
after that we can see all these things getting implemented,
so a huge
data is also
coming in front of us right now, I would
like to present that also in front of you, that is,
all of you know here that
how many people in India have total vehicles, so there
is a rough data, more than 30 crore,
around 30 crore vehicles can be seen
and according to this data, the
insurance of 50% of them, the tax insurance, has
expired here, they have
not renewed it, we are getting to see this thing
here, so definitely
these 50% who have not done this thing,
then obviously what can they do after this news, they
can go here to renew it, they
can get the tax insurance here, so this is one news
you are getting to see, by the way another data is coming out that it is being
said that it is
fine within 1 year  You know how many accidents happen on average?
You get four to five lakh
cases of road accidents.
So obviously, insurance
is very important. You all
know this, and many laws have been made related to this. But if you
see, you
all know that no one is afraid of anyone, people are seen
driving freely here. That is why, at
this time, we have
decided to
implement it 100%.
Those who have not taken insurance here
or have not done so, they will get a
notice from the State
Transport Department. Plus, along with that,
you can also be fined here.
So, one point you should definitely
know here. So this was the news.
Now friends, let's go to which companies
you can focus on for study purposes if you want
because as always, I
want to demonstrate that so many news keep
coming, so due to this, you will have to
tell the shares that the company may benefit from it.
So, the disclaimer is that this is
not a bank selling recommendation.  Yes, if we
talk about general insurance, especially tax
insurance, then ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company, if you
want, you can keep this company on your radar. If
seen, the company is available here only for around ₹1000.
If we talk about the maximum return pattern, then
what is the performance of the company from 2017 till now,
returns of around 60% are being seen here,
so the company is not a bad company, it is a
good company, yes, it should not be said
that it only gives returns, almost the company Bhuriya
is good, if seen from the long term, then a
decent company is seen here, so
we will come to this after some time, there is
another company
which deals related to this, that is,
tax insurance, general insurance, so
friends, the name of this company is New India
Assurance Company and you all know that
this is a government company, so
if we talk about this company, friends,
if you are thinking of investing in it, then
I think it will be
better if you award the right
share holding of the company.  If you check the pattern,
we are seeing more than 75%.
In between, due to Covid, we got
to see a lot of exclusives, hence one should be cautious
and along with that,
if I also show the maximum chat pattern of the
company, then you can see the condition of
this company, there has been a decline of 70%.
Since we saw this in the market in 2017, till now, we have seen a
continuous decline.
So, its competitor which we want to
see is ICICI Lombard,
it also came in 2017, so at least
some returns are being seen in it,
so you should also know which shares should not be bought. So, if you
want to go for it, you can go for it, I
cannot stop you from doing so, but yes, this company does
not appear to be that fundamentally strong. If you
want to consider investment, then there is no
reason for trading.
So, from an investment point of view, if you
want, you can consider ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company.  You
can definitely keep this on your radar. If we
talk about some other specifications of the company, then
this is a large sized midcap company. It
means it is a midcap company, but if we look at midcap as well, then
yes, we are
currently seeing a midcap market of Rs 50-55000 crore. If we
talk about face value, return on equity capital
employed, then you can easily see that here. I would
like to save a little bit about the
recent performance of the company and let us
see it here. So you can check the PNL of the company,
before this the
net profit was around Rs 1100 crore, which
came in the range of Rs 1400, then you can see a
slight decline to Rs 1200 and then again now we are
seeing the net profit going back to Rs 1600. If we
talk about this here, then the shareholding
pattern is of this group, so obviously
this point will be known that the
maximum promoter holding will be 48%.  The
promoter is getting it. If we
talk about F, it is 23%. If we talk about DS, it is
around 16 to 17%. The government also has a
small stake, not much. And if we
talk about the public, then around 11:30 to 12%. The
state public is also getting a share.
So, if we talk about the
news, I have put it in front of you.
And which shares to study, I have also
put it in front of you. If you
want, you can ignore New Indian. If you
want, you can study ICICI Lombard General Insurance
in detail. If I do this, then
definitely like and share it.
If you have not opened your demat account yet, then
you will definitely find a list of 25 videos in the description below. Mention
your name and which account have you
opened through your link properly in the comment
section. All the lectures will be made available before me
so that you
can learn from the share market. So, bye bye for that.